A racing second hand, a shimmering nebula!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، سديمٌ لامع
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts dried by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان دواء ممتاز للقلوب !التي جفّفها المجتمع الحديث
Today's case is in a general hospital! Old Mori's a killer?!
!تقع قضيّة اليوم في مشفى عام !العمّ موري قاتل؟
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
East Beika General Hospital
مشفى شرق بيكا العام
I'm so bored.
أشعر بالضجر
Oh, Dad...
...بربّك يا أبي
This is the old man's 3rd week in the hospital.
هذا الأسبوع الثالث على إقامة العمّ في المشفى
He broke his leg while trying to catch a criminal...
كسر ساقه وهو يصارع لصّاً حاول الإمساك به
...but naturally, I took him down instead.
لكن بالطبع كنتُ أنا من أطاح به
But, you've been so busy lately that this is a good chance to relax.
لكنّك كنت مشغولاً كثيراً مؤخراً لذا هذه فرصة مناسبة للاسترخاء
It's meal time!
!وقت الطعام
Food, at last!
!طعام أخيراً
The famous detective sure has an appetite!
يبدو أنّ المحقق الشهير يتضوّر جوعاً
How I'd love some beer and sashimi...
...كم أودّ أكل ساشيمي مع جعّة
That's not how a famous detective acts, Dad! How pathetic!
!لا يليق هذا بمتحرٍّ شهير يا أبي! يا للخزي
Nakayama Kazumi (26) Nurse
(26) ناكاياما كازومي ممرضة
But everyone is gossiping about wanting to see the famous Mori-san!
لكنّ جميع الممرضات يتكلّمن عن رغبتهن !برؤية موري-سان الشهير بأمّ أعينهن
Nurses in white, gossiping about me?!
الحسناوات ذوات الرداء الأبيض يتكلّمن عني؟
Yes!
!نعم
I'd love to hear some stories, myself!
أودّ سماع قصصك بدوري
Shirai Mitsuo (40) Physician
(40)  شيراي ميتسو الطبيب المسؤول
I could learn a lot!
قد أتعلّم الكثير
You're too kind, Dr. Shirai... How embarrassing!
،هذا إطراءٌ كثير أيّها الطبيب شيراي ستجعلني أخجل
Learn a lot of what?!
تتعلّم ماذا؟
Be careful you're not made into a guinea pig, Detective!
احترس من ألّا يستغلّك في تجاربه حضرة المتحرّي
How rude!
!يا للفظاظة
Eto Katsutoshi (40) Surgeon
(40) إيتو كاتسوتوشي جرّاح
Ooooh! What a scary look!
!يا للنظرة المخيفة
Detective, if I'm ever killed, Dr. Shirai will have done it!
حضرة المتحرّي، إذا قُتلت فاعرف أنّ شيراي هو الفاعل
Who was that?
من كان ذاك؟
That was Eto-kun, a fellow surgeon. We attended college together.
.إنّه إيتو-كن، جرّاح زميل لي ارتدنا الجامعة سويّاً
He has a sharp tongue, but he's a talented surgeon.
إنّه سليط اللسان، لكنّه جرّاح بارع
He may be talented, but he's a jerk.
قد يكون بارعاً، لكنّه فظيع الشخصيّة
It's started raining. Maybe we should get going, Conan-kun?
المطر يهطل، هل نرجع يا كونان-كن؟
Okay.
نعم
Mori-san, you can't have alcohol, but you can have some coffee.
،موري-سان، لا يمكنك شراب الساكي لكن يمكنك احتساء قهوة
Could I trouble you for a story?
هلّا أسمعتني بعضاً من قصص إنجازاتك؟
Sure!
!بالطبع
This latest case was a good one I solved using my great skills!
القضيّة الأخيرة مثال ممتاز للجرائم التي حللتُها باستنتاجاتي الحادة
It was ripe with mystery, as the killer had left not a thing behind!
فقد كانت مغلفةً بالغموض بما أنّ المجرم لم يترك أيّ شيء وراءه
Yikes! He's got a real sweet tooth!
!يحبّ السكّريات كثيراً
Huh? Where's Dr. Shirai?
ماذا؟ أين الطبيب شيراي؟
It's already this late?
تأخّر الوقت لهذا الحدّ؟
A murder!
!جـ-جريمة قتل
Call the police!
!اتّصلوا بالشرطة
Someone's being murdered! Call 110! Hurry!
!هناك جريمة قتل! اتّصلوا بـ 110 بسرعة
Right away!
!حاضر، فوراً
Wait, Mori-san!
!انتظر يا موري-سان
This room is empty!
هذه الغرفة فارغة
Huh? I could swear it was in here...
...ماذا؟ أنا متأكد أنّي رأيتُ هنا
The body disappeared?!
اختفت الجثّة؟
That's the only possibility, but I did see it...
...ذاك الاحتمال الوحيد، لكنّي رأيت فعلاً
You sure there ever was one?!
أأنت متأكّد من وجود واحدة في الأصل؟
Are you doubting me?!
!أتشكّ بي؟
But it's a fact that there was nothing--
...لكنّ الحقيقة أنّنا لم نجد شيئاً
Now, now. It's late. You'll disturb the patients.
مهلكما، الوقت متأخّر فعلينا ألّا نزعج المرضى
Let's call it a night--
...لننصرف الليلة
Doctor! I saw it with my own two eyes--
...يا طبيب! رأيتُ بأمّ عيني
You've been quite exhausted lately.
بدوتَ مرهقاً كثيراً مؤخراً
Well, I guess I did fall asleep while telling you my story...
حسناً، لعلّي نمتُ بينما كنت ...أقصّ عليك قصتي
So, the famous detective was tired. Talk about a panic monger...
كان المتحرّي الشهير مرهقاً فحسب إذاً
Well, we'll be leaving, too.
سننصرف نحن بدورنا
Thank you for your time!
شكراً لكم
However, the old man witnessed the same thing many more times!
لكن العمّ شاهد نفس المنظر مرّات عديدة متتالية
There's no doubt about it this time!
!لا-لا شكّ هذه المرّة
110! Call 110!
!اتّصلي بـ 110! 110
Again?
مُجدداً؟
That's impossible...
...مستحيل
Excuse me!
المعذرة
What's with you, Dad?! This is the fourth time!
!ما الخطب يا أبي؟ هذه المرّة الرابعة
I'm not lying! I really did see it!
...لا أكذب، رأيتُ حقّاً... رأيت
Dad...
أبي
I can only guess that the stress of dealing with all those crimes
لعلّ الضغط من التعامل مع الكثير من الجرائم بصفته متحرياً شهيراً أثّر عليه
No! Those were no hallucinations!
!كلا! لم تكن تلك هلوسات
Dad! Calm down! Pull yourself together!
!اهدأ يا أبي! تماسك
What's happened to you?!
ما حلّ بك؟
Guess I'll check it out just to be safe...
سأتفقد المكان تحسّباً
These blotches were recently made...
هذه بقع حديثة
It did rain twice during the time he witnessed the murders...
هطل المطر مرّتين في الليلة التي شهد فيها العمّ الجرائم
In other words, this window was open then...
أي أنّ هذه النافذة كانت مفتوحة وقتها
His room is diagonal from here...
غرفته المقابلة من هنا
No curtains... Is that an unused room?
لا ستائر، أتلك غرفة غير مستعملة؟
That's it! Now I see!
!فهمت! هكذا إذاً
If the lights are on in that room at night,
،إذا أُضيئت المصابيح في تلك الغرفة ليلاً
the dark building behind it will cause the window to act like a mirror.
فستكون هذه النافذة كمرآة مع المبنى المظلم وراءها
And, depending on the angle of the open window,
،وبناءً على زاوية فتحك للنافذة
it'll project into a certain room...
...يمكنك عكس صورة غرفة ما
...the old man's!
!وتلك غرفة العمّ
The real room isn't visible from his window.
لا يمكن رؤية غرفة الجريمة من نافذته مباشرةً
What's in that room...
...ما بالغرفة
...is reflected onto this window...
يُعكس على هذه النافذة
...and looks to him as if it's happening in here!
!فيبدو للعمّ أنّ هناك جريمة تقع هنا
This is a mirror trick involving windows!
!هذه خدعة مرآة باستعمال النوافذ
Storeroom
مخزن
This is it!
!هذا هو
A first-aid dummy...
دمية إسعافات أوليّة
They used this to act it out...
اُستعملت للتمثيل
Is this just a prank, or is there another reason behind it?
أهذا مجرّد مقلب أم يحمل معنى آخر وراءه؟
I'm gonna stay with him tonight to look after him!
!سأبقى الليلة مع العمّ للاعتناء به
How nice of you!
يا لاهتمامك
Well, Mori-san, take these and get some sleep.
إذاً يا موري-سان، تناول هذه واسترح رجاءً
It's really coming down.
المطر يهطل بشدّة
Well, good night!
عُمتما مساءً
Old man!
!يا عمّ
Conan! Did you see that, too?!
كونان! أرأيت ذلك أيضاً؟
Yeah! That was no hallucination!
!نعم! لم تكن هلوسة
I didn't think so!
!كما ظننت
Ok!
!حسنٌ
Mori Kogoro's back!
!رجع موري كوغورو
Storeroom
مخزن
There's nobody here, and the dummy hasn't been used...
لا أحد هنا، ولا يبدو أنّ الدمية قد اُستعملت
What does that mean?
ما معنى هذا؟
Oh, no! This is bad!
!أيمكن؟ تبّاً
Old man!
!يا عمّ
Dr. Eto!
!طبيب إيتو
There are two stab wounds on the body,
تلقّت الجثة طعنتين
and there were no vital reactions on the second one.
ولم تكن هناك تفاعلات حيوية مع الطعنة الثانية
So, the first killed him...
أي أنّ الأولى قتلته؟
Mori-kun!
!موري-كن
What happened here?!
ما الذي حصل هنا؟
I'm not entirely sure, myself...
...لستُ متأكداً بدوري
Someone suddenly hit me and...
...ضربني أحدهم فجأةً و
Dad!
!أبي
What on earth's going on?!
ما الذي يجري؟
I'm not really sure...
...لستُ متأكداً
Conan-kun! What happened?!
كونان-كن! ما الذي حصل؟
I don't know, either-
...لا أعرف بدوري
Mori-san killed Eto-kun?!
!موري-سان قتل إيتو-كن؟
Doesn't surprise me...
لا يفاجئني ذلك
Pardon me, but who are you?
المعذرة، من أنت؟
Mori-san's doctor, Shirai. I'm on night duty tonight...
،الطبيب شيراي المسؤول عن موري-سان لديّ مناوبة ليلية اليوم
You said that this doesn't surprise you...
قلتَ أنّ الأمر لا يفاجئك
Oh, Mori-san has been under a lot of stress lately, you see...
كنت أقصد أنّ موري-سان تعرّض لضغط كبير مؤخراً
...he even had recurring hallucinations,
أصبح يرى هلوسات متكررة
so I was worried he might do something like this...
وكنتُ قلقاً من حصول شيء كهذا
But I saw the murder in the opposite room, too!
لكنّي رأيتُ الجريمة في الغرفة !المقابلة مع العمّ
I know how you feel, Conan-kun,
أتفهّم مشاعرك يا كونان-كن
but your testimony would be deemed as a cover for Mori-kun
لكنّ شهادتك ستُعتبر حمايةً لموري-كن
and most likely won't hold up in court.
ولن تصمد في المحكمة غالباً
You can't be serious...
...لا-لا يمكن
...come to think of it, my memory does go blank sometimes...
بالتفكير في الأمر، تتلاشى ذاكرتي أحياناً
I could have easily committed a murder during then!
!يمكن أنّي قتلت شخصاً وقتها
Old man...
...يا عمّ
What?!
!ما الذي تقوله؟
Stop being stupid! Pull yourself together, Dad!
!لا تتفوّه بحماقات! تماسك يا أبي
Now, now, Ran-kun...
...هوّني عليك يا ران-كن
Anyway, from the locations of the room, stairs, elevators,
بأيّ حال، بناءً على موقع غرفة الجريمة والأدراج والمصاعد
and nurse stations, it's unlikely the killer snuck in from outside.
ومركز الممرضات فلا يُرجّح أنّ القاتل تسلّل من الخارج
Incidentally, I hear you and the victim had heated disagreements?
بالمناسبة، سمعت أنّ بينك والضحيّة اختلافات حادة يا طبيب شيراي
No, nothing that big!
!كلا، لا شيء كبير كهذا البتّة
Nevertheless, could I have your alibi?
هلّا أخبرتنا بحجّة غيابك بأيّ حال؟
Yes. It happened at 11:30, right?
حاضر، وقعت الجريمة عند الحادية عشرة والنصف، صحيح؟
I was in my own room on the 2nd floor of the north ward.
كنتُ في غرفتي ذاك الوقت في الطابق الثاني من الجناح الشمالي
Can you prove this?
أيمكنك إثبات ذلك؟
Okita-kun. You delivered my charts at about that time, right?
أوكيتا-كن، قمتِ بتسليمي سجّلات في ذاك الوقت، صحيح؟
Yes. It was around then.
نعم، كان قرابة ذاك الوقت
And you're certain he was in the room at the time?
وأنتِ متأكّدة أنّه كان في الغرفة وقتها؟
Yes. He was on the phone, though...
أجل، لكنّه كان يتكلّم على الهاتف
Dr. Shirai.
طبيب شيراي
I brought your charts. And some coffee.
أحضرتُ السجّلات، معها قهوة أيضاً
Oh, thanks!
!شكراً
I'm on the phone, so could you just leave 'em on the desk?
،أنا أتكلّم على الهاتف الآن هلّا تركتِها على المكتب؟
Okay!
حسناً
It was just then that all this happened...
حصلت هذه الجلبة في ذاك الوقت تقريباً
So, although you didn't see him, you're sure you spoke with him
تكلّمتِ معه إذاً رغم أنّك لم تريه؟
and not a recording?
ولم يكن تسجيلاً؟
Yes.
صحيح
So my alibi checks out, Inspector.
حجّة غيابي ثابتة إذاً حضرة المفتّش
But what kind of call was it?
لكن ما كانت المكالمة؟
Did you call them, or did they call you?
هل أنت من اتّصل؟ أم تلقّيت الاتّصال؟
What's that matter?
وما المهم؟
Well?
إذاً؟
An anonymous person had called to complain about my diagnosis.
اتّصل بي شخص مجهول للتذمّر من تشخيصي له
You get them once in a while.
يحصل ذلك من حينٍ لآخر
In other words, we can't ID the caller.
أي لا يمكننا التثبّت من هويّة المتّصل
Which means Mori-kun is the most suspect...
ما يعني أنّ موري-كن هو الأكثر شبهة
What?!
!لا يُعقل
Is that really so?
أحقّاً ذلك؟
Dr. Shirai's alibi does seem airtight. But...
تبدو حجّة الطبيب شيراي مطبقة حقّاً
Dr. Shirai clearly opened the old man's curtains
فتح الطبيب شيراي ستائر غرفة العمّ
and set the alarm clock
ووقّت ساعة التنبيه
so he would witness those murder scenes...
كي يشهد تلك الجرائم بكلّ وضوح
But that alibi of his...
...لكن حجّة غيابه
Shirai
شيراي
A speakerphone...
هاتف بخاصية تكبير صوت
He didn't use any sugar...
لم يضف سكّراً
That's it! Now I understand his alibi trick!
!فهمت! عرفت حيلة حجّة غيابه
No doubt about it! The killer was Dr. Shirai!
!لا شكّ في الأمر! القاتل هو الطبيب شيراي
But I have no proof...
لكن لا دليل لديّ
Wait. Could this coffee cup...
...لحظة، أيمكن أنّ كأس القهوة هذا
Hey, Mister Examiner!
سيّدي المُحلل
Oh, the boy staying with Mori-san!
أنتَ الفتى الذي يقيم مع موري-سان
Things don't look so good this time...
يبدو أنّ وضعه صعب هذه المرّة
Actually, Inspector Megure said he wants you to check something.
في الواقع، أخبرني المفتّش ميغوري أنّه يريد منك فحص شيء
Shirai
شيراي
So?!
!إذاً؟ ما الذي وجدته؟
Yeah, it was just like you said!
نعم، كما قلتَ تماماً يا فتى
I thought so!
!كما ظننت
I found proof on the coffee cup that Dr. Shirai was the killer!
وجدتُ الدليل على كأس القهوة !الذي يدين الطبيب شيراي
Here it comes, Inspector!
!بدأت حضرة المفتّش
What?!
!ماذا؟
What's going on, Megure-san?!
ما الخطب يا ميغوري-سان؟
Don't worry! This is the unique pose "Sleeping Kogoro" takes
"لا تقلق، هذه وضعيّة "كوغورو النائم التي يتّخذها موري-كن
when using his logic!
!عندما يبدأ شرح استنتاجاته
This is a cleverly devised two-step crime, everyone.
يا سادة، هذه جريمة مدبّرة بمكر تتكوّن من خطوتين
The first step was to mentally drive me into a corner enough
الخطوة الأولى كانت هي الإثقال عليّ ذهنياً
to convince me and everyone else that I committed a murder
لإقناعي والجميع أنّي قد أرتكب جريمة
out of stress.
تحت الضغط النفسيّ
The second step was to commit that murder
والخطوة الثانية هي ارتكاب القاتل للجريمة وتلفيق التهمة بي
and then execute his alibi trick to avoid being suspected himself.
ثمّ تنفيذه حيلة حجّة غيابه ليهرب من دائرة الشبهة
To do so, he first used the first-aid dummy in the fourth floor storeroom.
لفعل ذلك، استعمل القاتل دمية الإسعافات الأوليّة في مخزن الطابق الرابع أوّلاً
The killer opened the murder room window at a certain angle
فتح القاتل نافذة غرفة الجريمة بزاوية محددة
and made his fake murders in the storeroom reflect off of it
...وجعل جرائمه المزيّفة في المخزن تنعكس
so that I would see it from the south ward.
بحيث أستطيع رؤيتها في الجناح الجنوبي
And then, at 11:30,
ثمّ، الحادية عشرة والنصف من هذه الليلة
he called the victim into the room and murdered him.
استدعى الضحيّة لتلك الغرفة وقتله
Just like his previous acts, but this time for real.
بنفس أسلوب تمثيله السابق، لكن بتطبيق فعليّ هذه المرّة
That's what Conan and I witnessed.
ذلك ما شهدتُه وكونان
But how could he get you to witness it so conveniently?
لكن كيف يستطيع جعلكما تشهدانها وفقما يريد؟
To do that, the killer visited my room, opened the curtains,
لفعل ذلك، أتى القاتل لغرفتي وفتح الستائر
and had me take an adjusted amount of sleeping medicine.
وجعلني أتجرّع كميّة محسوبة من حبوب منوّمة
In addition, he set the alarm clock to 11:30, the time of the murder.
فوق ذلك، ضبط ساعة التنبيه على الحادية عشرة والنصف، وقت الجريمة
He then knocked me out with a blunt object after I rushed into the room
ثمّ ضربني بأداة صلبة وأفقدني الوعي بعدما هرعتُ لمسرح الجريمة
and put the knife in my hand to get my fingerprints on it.
وجعلني أمسك بالسكّين لترك بصماتي عليه
Who, exactly?!
!من فعل ذلك؟
Don't tell me you did it...
...أ-أيمكن أنّ الطبيب شيراي
Isn't that what you want to say, Mori-san?
ذلك ما تريد قوله، صحيح يا موري-سان؟
Yes. Dr. Eto's murderer was you, Dr. Shirai!
نعم، قاتل الطبيب إيتو كان أنت !يا طبيب شيراي
But I have an alibi, Mori-san.
لكن لديّ حجّة غياب يا موري-سان
He's right, Mori-kun!
!ذلك صحيح يا موري-كن
He had her deliver the charts then, and he even talked with her!
طلب من هذه الممرضة تسليم سجّلات !في ذاك الوقت وكلّمها
It wasn't a recording, either!
!ولم يكن تسجيلاً
It was the cell phone.
كان هاتفه الخلويّ
Cell phone?
هاتف خلويّ؟
First, the doctor called his cell phone from his room just after 11:00,
أوّلاً، اتّصل الطبيب بهاتفه الخلويّ من غرفته بعد الحادية عشرة بقليل
turned on the speaker, and went to the murder room in the north ward.
وفعّل وضعية مكبّر الصوت، وذهب لغرفة الجريمة في الجناح الشمالي
He then murdered Dr. Eto, who he had called there ahead of time,
قتل هناك الطبيب إيتو الذي استدعاه سلفاً
used the body to act out a murder at 11:30,
واستعمل الجثّة لتمثيل الجريمة عند الحادية عشرة والنصف
and then used his cell phone to converse with the nurse over the phone.
ثمّ استعمل هاتفه الخلويّ للكلام مع الممرضة عبر الهاتف الثابت
Then, when I arrived on the scene, he hit me with a blunt object,
ثمّ، عندما وصلتُ لمسرح الجريمة ضربني بأداة صلبة
knocked me out, and put the knife in my hands to put my prints on it.
أفقدني الوعي، جعلني أمسك السكّين فأترك بصماتي
Finally, he returned to his room during the commotion
بعدها، رجع لغرفته أثناء الفوضى
and turned the phone off.
وأطفأ الهاتف
He must have felt quite relieved that it was all over.
لا بدّ أنّه شعر بارتياح آنذاك لظنّه أن كلّ شيء انتهى
But he made one big oversight.
لكنّه ارتكب خطأً كبيراً في حساباته
The coffee the nurse kindly brought him.
كان القهوة التي جلبتها الممرضة
I assume you all know Dr. Shirai has a real sweet tooth?
تعرفن جميعاً أنّ الطبيب شيراي يحب السكّريات، صحيح؟
However, the coffee's sugar hadn't been used at all.
لكنّ السكّر مع القهوة لم يُستعمل أبداً
This means Dr. Shirai hadn't drunk the coffee.
هذا دليل على أنّ الطبيب شيراي لم يشرب القهوة
Ridiculous. Even I take it without sugar sometimes.
سخافة، حتّى أنا أشربها دون سكّر أحياناً
I would hardly call that proof.
لن ينفع ذلك كدليل
So, then you did drink it?
شربتها بالفعل إذاً؟
Yeah, but if you're going to say how there was no saliva on it,
نعم، لكن إذا كنت ستذكر عدم وجود لعاب على الكأس
that might be because I gave it a quick rinse.
فذلك لأنّي غسلته سريعاً غالباً
There's something else missing.
هناك شيء آخر مفقود
Oh? What would that be?
حقّاً؟ وما هو؟
Your fingerprints. There aren't any on the coffee cup.
بصماتك، غير موجودة على الكأس
That's because I rinsed it...
...ذلك لأنّي غسلته
But the fingerprints of the nurse who brought it are on the handle.
لكنّ بصمات الممرضة التي جلبت القهوة موجودة على يد الكأس
Are you saying you washed off your fingerprints from on top of hers?
أتريد قول أنّك غسلت بصماتك فحسب من فوق بصماتها؟
That'd be impossible.
ذلك مستحيل
In short, when you rinsed the coffee cup, you had gloves on.
أي أنّك عندما غسلت الكأس، كنت ترتدي قفّازات
The surgical gloves you had used during the murder...
قفّازات جراحية استعملتها في ارتكابك الجريمة
Why was he wearing gloves before then?
لمَ ظلّ مرتدياً القفّازات وقتها؟
When he returned to his room after the murder,
،عندما رجع لغرفته بعد ارتكاب الجريمة
he probably still had the weapon he hit me with.
كان لا يزال يحمل السلاح الذي ضربني به
He couldn't get his prints on it before he disposed of it.
لا يمكنه السماح بأن تنتقل بصماته له قبل تخلّصه منه
At any rate, once back in his room, he felt he had to down the coffee,
بأيّ حال، بعدما رجعت لغرفتك رأيت أنّ عليك سكب القهوة
or else his alibi of being in the room would seem suspect,
وإلا سيُشتبه بحجّة غيابك وكونك في الغرفة
so he hurriedly poured it out, with gloves still on, and rinsed the cup.
فسكبتها سريعاً وأنت ترتدي القفّازات وغسلت الكأس
But only the inside.
لكن داخله فحسب
For that reason, only the nurse's fingerprints remained on the cup.
لذلك بقيت بصمات الممرضة فحسب على الكأس
You said you drank the coffee.
قلتَ أنّك شربت القهوة
Are there any other reasons your fingerprints weren't on the handle?
أتوجد أسباب أخرى لعدم وجود بصماتك على الكأس؟
How ironic.
يا للسخرية
Leaving evidence because of the gloves I wore to leave no evidence...
تركتُ دليلاً بسبب قفّازات ارتديتها كيلا أترك دليلاً
So you admit to it?
تعترف إذاً؟
It's all as Mori-san said.
كلّ شيء كان كما قاله موري-سان
Why? What was your motive?!
لمَ؟ ما كان دافعك؟
Our chief surgeon is being forced to retire next month.
سيُجبر كبير الجرّاحين في المشفى على التقاعد الشهر المقبل
Eto and I were the candidates for his position...
كنتُ وإيتو المرشّحين لأخذ منصبه
But Eto blackmailed me into declining!
لكنّ إيتو ابتزني كي أستبعد نفسي
I had no choice but to accept his demand...
لم يكن بيدي سوى الانصياع لطلبه
He knew I had bought my way into medical school.
فقد كان يعرف أنّي دخلت كليّة الطب عبر الرشوة
After all, the professor I paid off was his father!
!والرشوة التي قدّمتُها للالتحاق كانت لوالده البروفسور
Why did I ever pay out all that money to get into school?
لمَ دفعتُ تلك الرشوة ودخلتُ المجال بشكل غير شرعي؟
In other words, crime and dishonesty doesn't pay, Doctor.
أي أنّ الخداع والجريمة لا يعودان لك بشيء يا طبيب
I hate this! I'm through with this Sleeping Kogoro stuff!
!يكفي! انتهيتُ من قصّة "كوغورو النائم" هذه
How come? You solved that case easily enough!
!لمَ؟ حللتَ القضيّة ببراعة
I did?
أنا؟
That's right!
صحيح
I guess old Sleeping Kogoro is still going strong after all!
!بالفعل إذاً! كوغورو النائم بصحّة وعافية
He never learns...
...مُسن لا يتّعلم
Teacher! Sonoko!
!سينسي! سونوكو
After she was knocked out with chloroform,
،بعدما أُفقدت وعيها بالكلوروفورم
she was strangled with a rope!
!خُنقت بحبل
There are still tracks here!
!لا تزال هناك آثار أقدام
The front door...
...الباب الأمامي
That means the killer is still inside this lodge!
!ما يعني أنّ الفاعل... لا يزال داخل النزل
On the next Conan:
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Ski Lodge Murder Case (Part 1)."
جريمة قتل نزل التزلّج (الجزء الأوّل)
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Heater.
جهاز تدفئة
Next episode is a two-parter.
الحلقة القادمة هي الجزء الأوّل ...من قضيّة بـ
Part one, part one, part one.
♪ الجزء الأوّل ♪